[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 30]
[Lai's Mansion]
I failed to handle things properly.
I didn't capture Shen Du in Yingzhou.
Fire Moth Sect in Yingzhou
is completely gone?
Yes.
Losers...
can't be kept.
You're badly injured.
It seems you'll need some time to recover.
Have those Half-faced Ghosts in Yingzhou
been dealt with?
I gave them poison beforehand.
There are no survivors!
Very good.
What about the thing
Mo Qianzhi left for Shen Du?
This is what Shen Du was looking for.
Mo Qianzhi
had been watching Yingzhou for so long.
He must have gathered dirt
on quite a few people in the court.
A poetry collection?
How could this be?
It must have been swapped
by Shen Du back then!
You've been fooled by Shen Du!
I...
[Daily Trade Correspondence]
Shen Du,
I'd like to see
how you plan to break out of this situation.
I never expected
that for all these years,
Minister Zhang's faction has been smuggling
with Xichen State through Gannan Area
to reap massive profits.
Even Princess Ying
has been bribing frontier soldiers
under the guise of funding to win their loyalty.
Senior secretly seized leverage
over two major factions in the court,
yet he never reported it.
I suppose he didn't trust the imperial court.
Chen Huo'e must have known something about this,
so she wanted to use me
to find this booklet.
So how do you plan to handle this?
I plan...
Grand Commander!
Grand Commander, bad news!
What's the panic?
The captured Half-faced Ghosts
died suddenly before we could
extract any information.
Grand Commander,
it seems they died from poison.
When they were captured,
I searched them thoroughly,
even
their teeth.
There was no chance
for them to ingest poison.
[There is a triangular needle wound on Yuanniang's body]
The needle mark...
How could this be?
You found something?
Jing Lin was right.
They must have been poisoned
with a slow-acting toxin
before their capture.
Coroner, can you
identify the poison?
Yes,
but it will take some time.
Report to me immediately once it's confirmed.
Yes, Grand Commander.
It's time to return to Xiang'an.
What are you reading?
Along the way,
we passed through
many places.
These
are notes I took from casual conversations
with the local people.
Have you noticed something unusual?
According to their recollections,
there is indeed something strange.
The year before the Shen family's case,
Cang State suffered from a flood.
Many people starved
due to food shortages.
In Gannan Area,
according to the people's recollections,
some areas
were also affected by the flood.
Logically,
there should have been insufficient grain.
But the local grain prices
fell significantly instead of rising.
So where did the suddenly appeared grain
come from?
You're suggesting…
There is indeed a possibility
that someone secretly
took grain from the official granaries.
Assassins!
Xing.
Let's go!
Don't linger!
Let's head to the palace!
Lord Shen, you truly care for the country like your own home.
You just entered the Imperial City,
and already rushed to the palace to report.
No wonder my mother
holds you in such high regard.
Your Highness, I'm flattered.
I'm merely doing my best,
hoping not to betray
the grand empress dowager's trust.
If you truly think this way,
that'd be great.
At least it won't disappoint
my mother's expectations for you.
I hope you can rise to great heights.
What do you mean by that, Your Highness?
Never mind.
It's late.
Jia'an, you must be tired too, right?
Shen Du,
come to my mansion later and we'll talk more.
Your Majesty, please have some tea.
Your Majesty,
they're here.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, wish you great health and prosperity.
Rise.
Mr. Shen,
I have read the memorial
you asked them to sent.
Mo Qianzhi is dead.
The rebels have been eradicated.
The Half-faced Ghosts have also been eliminated.
You handled the Yingzhou matter well.
During the investigation,
did you encounter any difficulties?
Your Majesty, thanks to your blessing,
everything went smoothly.
What reward should I
bestow upon you?
Shen Du is already the grand commander of the Imperial Security Bureau,
overseeing all levels of officials.
He's already a first-rank official.
So there's no higher position
to promote him to, right?
That mouth of yours...
It's only because I dote on you
that you speak so freely.
Fortunately,
Mr. Shen is not an outsider.
Otherwise,
people might think
I wanted to use you
to remind Mr. Shen.
Your Majesty, please forgive me.
It's my fault.
Mr. Shen,
what do you think?
Just tell me what reward
you want.
I will surely grant it.
That was merely my duty.
No reward is necessary.
During the Yingzhou mission,
if it weren't for my wife's help,
I'm afraid it wouldn't have gone so smoothly.
If a reward is to be given,
it should be given to Secretary Yan Xing.
So,
you want to seek a reward for your wife.
It seems that the trip to Yingzhou
has strengthened your bond.
I've done a good deed then.
You're wise, Your Majesty.
Rise.
Mr. Shen, you are truly a pillar of the state,
not claiming credit for your achievements.
Very well.
I'll reward
your wife
as you wish.
Ms. Yan, for your merits in pacifying Yingzhou's chaos,
you are promoted to Director under the Ministry of Justice,
sixth rank.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Ms. Yan,
is there any other
special reward you want?
Your Majesty,
there's
nothing else I want.
Are you sure?
This is a rare opportunity.
Every word I said is true.
I do not want a reward.
I only wish for peace and prosperity in this world.
Good.
Ms. Yan,
as a woman,
you still care for the world.
Cang State
truly needs
officials like you.
I heard that when you were in Yingzhou,
you encountered grave danger
and almost lost your lives.
Ask an imperial physician to their mansion to treat them.
Yes.
[Imperial Security Bureau]
What's wrong?
You just received a reward.
Why do you look so gloomy?
Director Yan.
I just realized it.
The matter in Yingzhou was significant.
The grand empress dowager had to grant a reward for form's sake.
But she didn't want to reward you.
That Zhang Baohuan
must have understood
her thoughts.
So he and Madam Xu played a duet,
deliberately saying there was no higher rank to grant.
They did that just to prevent you from claiming credit.
Had you not handled
the situation wisely,
who knows what might have happened?
What will you do
with the booklet
Lord Mo left you?
That booklet involves many people.
I'll find the right time to present it.
Even foxes can't outwit you.
You rushed into the palace in the dead of night
to request an audience in front of the grand empress dowager,
yet you didn't mention the booklet.
It was just a feint
to make certain people uneasy.
I'm afraid they
can't sleep well tonight.
You understand me best,
Honey.
So,
I received a reward by doing nothing?
Princess Ying said you're devoted to your duty,
but you don't need to
be devoted to your duty in the middle of the night
and not come home, right?
There's a place
I need to show you.
Let's go.
[Memorial Tablet of Shen Bingzhu, My Father]
This is...
This is what I want you
to know.
Back then, the Shen family was framed,
and my mother fell gravely ill.
She knew her time was short
and told me to write a confession.
I won't write it.
And I can't write it.
Father
would rather die to prove his innocence.
I'd rather die like Father
to prove our innocence.
But if even you die too,
this wrongful case
will truly be settled.
So many lives
of the Shen family
were wrongfully taken,
including your father's.
Their grievances
and the truth they always wanted
would die with them!
She also told me
to endure it for a while and become an official.
Only then would there be a chance
to clear the Shen family's name.
Since that day,
I have lived
for nothing but vengeance.
I've been carrying
the Shen family's resentment.
Seeking the truth of it
has become my
only reason to live.
Perhaps the world has already forgotten,
or no one cares anymore.
But I clearly remember
every innocent person
who died for the Shen family.
I dare not forget them even just for a moment.
Not just you.
Me too.
I remember.
I have never forgotten Uncle Shen.
[Memorial Tablet of Shen Bingzhu, My Father]
When the Shen family fell into trouble,
they said
Uncle Shen betrayed the country and colluded with the enemy.
I didn't believe it.
He was the most upright
and selfless person I've ever seen.
He would never do anything
to harm the country or its people.
So from that moment on,
I swore
to become a female official
and be admitted to the Ministry of Justice,
hoping that one day,
I could uncover the truth myself.
People call me the White Ghost,
so I've convinced myself
that I am indeed a lonely ghost,
drifting alone in this living hell.
I really didn't expect...
that there would be someone as foolish as me.
♫I hope you also look up and see the radiant stars and moon♫
You're warm,
alive and breathing.
How could you be a lonely ghost?
♫No matter how vast the world is, I'll wait for your appearance♫
Your heart
♫A quick glance at each other♫
is beating
with the expectations of so many people.
♫Has warmed the winter in memories♫
♫Don't mind the destined solitude, and shine brightly♫
From now on,
you won't be alone anymore.
♫I'll wait until the years blossom like flowers♫
I will do everything I can
♫The ice and snow slowly melted♫
to help you uncover the truth
and clear the Shen family's name.
♫I heard those tender words♫
♫He told her, "I love you"♫
♫What I saw in my dreams♫
♫Is not a flashy illusion♫
♫I don't fear the challenges ahead, riding a white horse to chase after time♫
♫Let's go together♫
♫Love is pure and flawless, indifferent to the changes of the world♫
♫Let's experience it together♫
[Memorial Tablet of Shen Bingzhu, My Father]
Go get the horse.
[Shen's Mansion]
Grand Commander,
Madam,
you're finally back.
Sorry for making you worried.
No rush, Honey.
I'm not.
[Shen's Mansion]
The ancestors of the Shen family,
thanks to your blessing,
[Shen's Mansion]
Grand Commander has finally come to understand.
He's come to understand.
It's late.
Honey, rest early.
Okay.
Where are you going?
To bed.
You and I
have something more important to do.
Shen Du, I...
♫Every memory, I hold it dear♫
♫From desolation, it has become a poem♫
♫Looking back♫
You said
♫We passed through the misty rain and waited for the sunny day♫
from now on, I won't
be alone anymore.
♫Love ripples in each other's eyes♫
Since you had the courage to barge in,
you won't be able to escape from now on.
♫You have long melted the frost in my heart♫
I am
♫So many words to say, but the paper isn't long enough♫
a woman
of my word.
♫Every day♫
♫We test and probe each other♫
♫And before we knew it, we reached forever♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫I want to keep you by my side♫
♫Through the obstacle of wind and rain♫
♫I want to be your moonlight♫
♫Accompany you until every dawn♫
♫How I wish♫
♫I could just forget the passage of time like this♫
♫I want to be with you, side by side♫
♫May we never forget each other♫
♫There will always be a place for us to meet♫
♫I want to be with you forever♫
♫When our black hair turns grey♫
♫In this life♫
♫I'll only cherish you in my heart♫
Deputy Minister Zhang is here.
[Peace and Prosperity]
The grand empress dowager sent me to bestow a reward.
Director in the Ministry of Justice,
Yan Xing,
has been rewarded with 10,000 bolts of silk
and 10,000 taels of gold,
in recognition of her merits
and to extend the imperial grace.
I thank the grand empress dowager for the rewards.
The grand empress dowager issued another decree.
The grand empress dowager has given her order.
Shen Du, Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau,
has quelled the rebellion
and secured harmony among the states.
His merits are unparalleled,
and his deeds shine across the land.
Princess Jia'an,
gentle and wise,
virtuous and graceful,
elegant
and well-educated,
is now of age
and unmarried.
These two are a match made in heaven.
Hence, I bestow marriage upon them.
May they devote themselves to the country,
united in hearts.
[Peace and Prosperity]
Grand Commander,
this is the grand empress dowager's decree.
It is not something
others can easily change.
At least, you should accept the decree first.
Deputy Minister Zhang, as you can see,
I have no intention
of marrying Princess Jia'an.
And my wife
doesn't want me to take another wife.
Please report that to the grand empress dowager.
Do you know why the grand empress dowager
[Peace and Prosperity]
sent me to read this decree?
This kind of thing
is supposed to be handled
by someone from the Imperial Astronomer's Office.
But why did she send me?
Why?
You don't understand,
but Grand Commander understands, right?
Please be straightforward
and explain clearly.
[Peace and Prosperity]
Since Han Shiyuan
has married into
the Yan family,
I'll explain to you,
so that Shiyuan won't blame me for no reason
when he learns of it in the future.
[Peace and Prosperity]
Think about it.
Princess Jia'an is the most cherished daughter
of Princess Ying.
And Princess Ying is
the grand empress dowager's most cherished princess.
Princess Ying and the grand empress dowager
are quite alike in temperament.
So Princess Ying has been the favorite,
even surpassing Prince Xian.
Yet now,
Princess Jia'an has been granted
to Grand Commander as his second wife.
What does it mean?
Grand Commander holds unrivaled power,
and his merits are outstanding.
And he enjoys
unparalleled glory and respect,
above all others.
But Grand Commander stands alone,
without any powerful backer.
Moreover...
he married you,
a sub-sixth-rank official.
Even if Princess Jia'an is to marry,
she should have her pick among the imperial
and noble families.
She doesn't need to marry Shen Du at all.
Your father said
Shen Du is the only one left in the Shen family.
Now the people related to the Shen family
are only Mo Qianzhi and the butler.
Mo Qianzhi is also dead.
So Shen Du is really
alone
in the court.
And he oversees all officials.
Even the slightest mistake
could easily cost his life.
So,
one must be willing to risk the child to catch the wolf.
Shen Du is that wolf.
[Peace and Prosperity]
Deputy Minister Zhang,
I can endure whatever precautions the grand empress dowager
takes against me.
But this marriage is unnecessary.
I already have a wife.
And I will not take another wife in this life.
Deputy Minister Zhang,
I'm going with you to the palace to decline the marriage.
[Peace and Prosperity]
Shen Du!
-Grand Commander!
-Shen Du!
[Peace and Prosperity]
You're disobeying my order!
Your Majesty,
my wife and I love each other very much.
Moreover, I oversee the imperial court
and scrutinize all officials, naturally earning resentment.
It is not a position of wealth or ease.
I do not wish for Princess Jia'an
to suffer by marrying me.
If it weren't for my arrangement,
you'd never have a chance to marry Princess Jia'an!
Princess Jia'an is of noble birth.
I know I am unworthy
and dare not covet her.
Your Majesty, please withdraw the decree.
You...
How dare you!
In all my years of service,
I have never sought anything for myself.
Only today,
Your Majesty, I beg you to withdraw the decree.
I swear I will repay this kindness
with my utmost loyalty, serving to my last breath!
Grand Commander Shen has always been loyal.
His sincerity is evident.
You must think twice.
Your Majesty,
I know you're
paving a path for me.
I have stood in this world with an untainted heart,
dedicating myself wholly to easing your burdens.
If my future depends on the marriage
with Princess Jia'an,
it means you
don't trust in my abilities.
Your Majesty!
What's the matter?
Something happened at Ming Hall.
What?
[Chengtian Gate]
The men I sent investigated multiple times.
They didn't find anything amiss.
But this time,
their greed
led them to make a mistake,
which exposed their scheme.
When we traced it back,
we uncovered the issue.
Someone kept dual ledgers.
Dual ledgers?
What does that mean?
Dual ledgers
mean one open ledger
using the Longmen accounting method
and one
secret ledger
using the four-feet accounting method.
Continue.
The open ledger
with the Longmen accounting method
was crafted with exceptional skills.
It looks
flawless on the surface.
That is why since Ming Hall's establishment,
none of the audits on the Ministry of Revenue's key officials
have uncovered any issues.
But
the newly discovered ledger
uses the four-feet accounting method.
So at first glance,
it looks entirely unrelated
to Ming Hall's accounts.
How much has been embezzled?
How dare they!
They actually embezzled
over 20 million taels of silver!
Every official involved in the reconstruction project
is implicated,
except Lord Zhang Baohuan.
Baohuan lacks expertise in accounts
and doesn't have the nerve.
However,
he was the overseer
of the Ming Hall project.
So he is guilty of dereliction of duty.
Send him away.
Ask him to rest quietly in the side yard.
Yes.
As for the others...
Those officials
belong to various factions in the court.
Various factions?
Including my Zhou family?
It's only my assumption.
Your Majesty, please forgive me.
You're not guilty.
I thought
despite the officials' different intentions,
they all cared about the country.
But I never expected
the corruption would fester in the shadows.
Now,
the undercurrents stir,
and men's hearts are unpredictable.
Your Majesty, you've devoted yourself to the country,
but the court officials
each have their own intentions.
Especially
since the incident with Mo Qianzhi,
the prefectural governor of Yingzhou,
no one has been appointed to succeed him in Gannan Area.
I think
they're all getting a bit impatient.
It's time to give them a warning.
Your Majesty,
Shen Du's Imperial Security Bureau
seldom interacts with others
and has always carried out its duties diligently.
He would make a good candidate.
However,
if he marries Princess Jia'an,
I'm afraid his hands may be tied
in future matters.
You want to help him.
You should first see if he's smart enough.
Keep the Ming Hall matter
under wraps for now.
Investigate secretly.
Yes.
Deliver my orders
to the Imperial Investigation Department
and the Imperial Security Bureau respectively.
[Chengtian Gate]
[Shen's Mansion]
You truly fear nothing.
I originally thought
I'd inevitably suffer some physical punishment,
but it turned out smoother than I imagined.
You mean
the marriage rejection matter is over just like that?
Not necessarily.
The grand empress dowager's anger
hasn't been vented yet.
But the marriage decree came about strangely.
I'm afraid it's related to that booklet.
I guess Princess Ying
was worried I would
present the evidence of her funding the Yingzhou troops,
so she told the grand empress dowager to arrange the marriage,
hoping to tie me down.
But unfortunately,
the grand empress dowager has no time for this.
Something serious happened at Ming Hall?
You knew about that long ago?
Shen Du,
so,
Madam Xu's report on the matter
was not a coincidence?
People don't know
Ming Hall holds special significance
for the grand empress dowager.
It witnessed the love
between the grand empress dowager and the late emperor.
After the fire at Ming Hall,
the grand empress dowager was extremely concerned
about its reconstruction.
She sent
her most trusted
Zhang Baohuan to oversee it
and decreed
the funding should have no upper limit.
No upper limit?
No upper limit
didn't mean the officials
could line their own pockets.
How much was involved?
I'm afraid it's enough to shake the entire court.
They've completely enraged
the grand empress dowager.